<resources>
    <string name="main_activity_name">CFOP Algorithms</string>
    <string name="cfop_activity_name">CFOP Information</string>
    <string name="cross_activity_name">Cross Information</string>
    <string name="f2l_activity_name">F2L Algorithms</string>
    <string name="oll_activity_name">OLL Algorithms</string>
    <string name="pll_activity_name">PLL Algorithms</string>


    <string-array name="main_list">
        <item>CFOP</item>
        <item>Cross</item>
        <item>F2L</item>
        <item>OLL</item>
        <item>PLL</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="main_list_description">
        <item>Information about the CFOP method</item>
        <item>Information about the cross</item>
        <item>First Tow Layers algorithms</item>
        <item>Permute Last Layer algorithms</item>
        <item>Orient Last Layer algorithms</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="webview_url">
        <item>https://alg.cubing.net/?stage=/</item>
        <item>&amp;type=alg&amp;alg=</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="cfop_title">CFOP</string>
    <string name="cfop_description">CFOP (Cross, F2L, OLL, PLL, pronounced C-F-O-P or C-fop) is a 3x3 speedsolving method proposed by several cubers around 1981. It is also known as the Fridrich Method after its popularizer, Jessica Fridrich. In part due to Fridrich\'s publication of the method on her website in 1995, CFOP has been the most dominant 3x3 speedcubing method since around 2000, with it and its variants used by the vast majority of the top speedcubers such as Feliks Zemdegs, Max Park, Sebastian Weyer, Mats Valk, etc </string>

    <string name="cfop_first_title">Origin and Naming</string>
    <string name="cfop_first_paragraph">"Jessica Fridrich is often erroneously credited as the sole inventor of CFOP. In reality, many developments were made in the early '80s by other cubers who have contributed to the method in its current form. The constituent techniques and their original proposers are as follows:

Cross: David Singmaster
F2L (4x corner + edge pairs): René Schoof
OLL/PLL: Hans Dockhorn, Anneke Treep, with many algorithms developed by Jessica Fridrich

During the resurgence in speedcubing's popularity in the late '90s and early 2000s, there was a general lack of information on the sport. Fridrich's website offered a vast wealth of information for those entering the sport, including a full description of CFOP with complete lists of algorithms. As a result, many who learned from her website began to call this method the "Fridrich Method," which explains the common use of the term today.

Several high-profile cubers have long disputed this terminology; Ron van Bruchem, famously, has publicly written that he will never call CFOP the "Fridrich Method." This issue has become well-advertised within the cubing community around the year 2008, likely because of this. The term "CFOP" has since seen increasing usage compared to back then, also in part motivated by efforts to standardize terminology in method classification, and is now seen, commonly, as "Fridrich Method."

While some cubers still insist on the term "CFOP," Fridrich's contribution to the popularization of the method is undeniable, and many others accept the term "Fridrich Method" as established terminology and a perfectly valid synonym for "CFOP.""
    </string>

    <string name="cfop_second_title">Steps</string>
    <string name="cfop_second_paragraph">CFOP can be viewed as an advanced version of a Layer-By-Layer method. In particular, it combines some steps of the said method into one by using many more algorithms. Here, we outline pure CFOP without any additional trick. Also, the cube is commonly solved with the white side on top for the cross, yellow on the bottom for the cross, and opposite for the other steps. However, it is NOT required.</string>
    <string name="f2l_toolbar_content">
        "First Two Layers, or F2L are normally the first two bottom layers of the 3x3x3 cube, or essentially all layers up until the last layer on larger cubes.

        The definition is a little different depending on the subject or who you are talking to. Usually, it refers to the part of the CFOP and CFCE methods that solve the first two layers in pairs, excluding the cross step.

        2-gen F2L, most pairs (30 of 41) have the edge sitting in the U-layer having two orientations, it shows R or F colour at the side. If it is the R colour you can solve the pair using only RU and if it is the F colour you can turn the cube (y&apos;) and solve the pair to the back slot using only RU. The only pairs that needs both R and F turns are the six ones with the edge unoriented in the slot, if the edge is oriented in the slot both ways works."
    </string>


    <string-array name="CFOPList">
        <item>Cross</item>
        <item>F2L</item>
        <item>OLL</item>
        <item>PLL</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="CFOPList_Descriptions">
        <item>Make a cross on one side by solving all edges of a given face. A Make sure to align the edges with the second-layer centers.

It is recommended that you solve the cross on the bottom, left, right or back face and that you become familiar doing the cross with all colors; not just one.</item>
        <item>Fill in the four slots between the cross pieces, one slot at a time. Each slot is filled by inserting a corner and its corresponding edge simultaneously. Most of the 41 cases have reasonable intuitive solutions. The completion of this step leaves one with just the last layer, typically placed on top.</item>
        <item>Make the entire top side (the last layer) of the cube a solid color. 57 nontrivial cases.

Those new to OLL break up the step into two. This greatly reduces the number of cases; 2-look OLL has 9 cases. However, note that this is a few seconds slower</item>
        <item>Finally, you finish the cube by permuting the top layer of the cube. 21 nontrivial cases.

Those new to PLL break up the step into two. This greatly reduces the number of cases; 2-look PLL has 6 cases. However, note that this is a few seconds slower</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="oll_list">
        <item>OLL 1</item>
        <item>OLL 2</item>
        <item>OLL 3</item>
        <item>OLL 4</item>
        <item>OLL 5</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="oll_list_description">
        <item>Information about the CFOP method</item>
        <item>Information about the cross</item>
        <item>First Tow Layers algorithms</item>
        <item>Permute Last Layer algorithms</item>
        <item>Orient Last Layer algorithms</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="f2l_youtube_video_url">Ar_Zit1VLG0</string>
    <string name="toolbar_tipp">Pull here for more information</string>
    <string name="oll_toolbar_content">"OLL (short for Orientation of the Last Layer) is a last-layer step for 3x3 that orients all last-layer corners and edges in one step. It is the first last-layer step in many speedsolving methods, including the Fridrich Method. OLL is usually followed by PLL.
        OLL is the 3rd step of the CFOP, and the &quot;busiest&quot; in respect of the amount of algorithms required to complete it. There are 57 different OLL variations, therefore needed 57 different algorithms to learn in order to complete the OLL step in just 1 algorithm. It is best to start with 2 look OLL and navigate your way around the full OLL."</string>
    <string name="oll_youtube_video_url">JvqGU0UZPcE</string>
    <string name="pll_toolbar_content">"PLL is the acronym for Permutation of the Last Layer. Permutation of the Last Layer is the last step of many speedsolving methods. In this step, the pieces on the top layer have already been oriented (OLL) so that the top face has all the same color, and they can now be moved into their solved positions. There are 21 PLLs (13 if you count mirrors and inverses as being the same) and each one is named after a letter. The following page gives a list of all of the PLLs, along with a picture and a list of common algorithms for each one. The diagrams below are top views of where you want the pieces to go. For example, the T Permutation (or &apos;T perm&apos;) swaps the UL and UR edges, as well as the UFR and UBR corners. If you like, try out all of the available algorithms for a case to see which one feels the fastest to you - the same algorithm may not be the fastest for everyone, and shorter algorithms are not always faster than longer ones. PLL is a subgroup of ZBLL."</string>
    <string name="pll_youtube_video_url">JvqGU0UZPcE</string>

    <string name="cross_title">The cross</string>
    <string name="cross_description">
    "Solving the cross is the first step of the CFOP, it consists of solving the 4 edge pieces of the first layer you choose to start with. After solving them correctly they will form a shape of &quot;cross&quot;. This step is exactly the same as the first step of the beginner&apos;s method, so you should already know how to do it, however with one difference: Solving the cross on the bottom of the cube instead on top. Thus saves the need of flipping the cube upside down during the solving which saves valuable time, and allows much faster shifting to the next step. Solving the cross on the bottom will also allow looking ahead for the next step, which is a key principle in speedcubing. It is ok to keep solving the cross on top, however I highly recommended starting to practice solving it on the bottom already.

    Solving the cross on the bottom won&apos;t be natural at the beginning, mostly due to the fact that you don&apos;t see the being solved pieces. Another con of solving the cross on the bottom is that it&apos;s harder to realize you&apos;d misplaced one of the pieces, which will cost valuable time and setback in resolving the cube.

    Just keep practicing solving the cross on the bottom. It will take longer than solving it on top in the beginning, however after some practicing it will become much easier and worthwhile. Don&apos;t afraid to look at the bottom of the cube during your solving at the beginning, after some practice you&apos;ll be able to avoid this habit.

    Choosing a color: Most of the speedcubers chooses white as the color to start with and solve the cross on. Choosing a color and sticking to it is important, as you will get to know this color-scheme by heart, and get faster recognition for the pieces to solve in next steps (mostly in the F2L).

        Solving the cross is based on intuitive moves only, no algorithms required."
    </string>
    <string name="cross_youtube_video_url">x93VB_v5ATM</string>

</resources>
